<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>International Crisis Group - CrisisWatch </title>
    <description />
    <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/RSS%20feeds/CrisisWatch.aspx</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 01:18:33 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 20:34:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en</language>
    <generator>Sitecore CMS: http://www.sitecore.net. Sitecore RSS module: Sitecore.Modules.RSS, Version=1.3.2.20378, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=null</generator>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/crisisgroup-crisiswatch" /><feedburner:info uri="crisisgroup-crisiswatch" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:browserFriendly></feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°152 | Tracking Conflict Worldwide</title>
      <description>The month saw violent extremist movements, including the Islamic State (IS) and al-Qaeda-linked groups, carry out major deadly attacks in Turkey, Pakistan, Côte d’Ivoire, Tunisia and Belgium. In Libya, the arrival of Prime Minister Serraj in Tripoli despite warnings from multiple factions could lead to further destabilisation. Meanwhile in Central Africa, political violence rose in Burundi and could break out in Chad around the 10 April presidential election. Yemen, South Sudan and even Syria saw progress, of varying degrees, toward peace talks or implementation of agreements, and in Colombia the start of talks between the state and the National Liberation Army (ELN) could lead to the end of the 52-year-old conflict.
</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/152.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 20:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/152.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°151 | Tracking Conflict Worldwide</title>
      <description>The month saw conflict continue to rage in Turkey’s south east between Ankara and the Kurdistan Workers’ Party (PKK), looking likely to further escalate in March. Afghanistan and Somalia both saw armed insurgencies capture new territories. In Africa, political tensions rose in Chad, Mozambique and Zimbabwe, while in Venezuela, deadlock between the opposition-held parliament and government has brought the country closer to political and economic implosion. In Asia, North Korea’s announcement of a satellite launch in violation of UN Security Council resolutions prompted international condemnation and calls for tough new sanctions. On a positive note, the coming month brings the possibility of a final agreement to end Colombia’s decades-old insurgency. 
</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/151.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 17:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/151.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°150 | Tracking Conflict Worldwide</title>
      <description>The month saw an intensification of Yemen’s war, amid heightened regional rivalries between Saudi Arabia and Iran complicating prospects for peace. Political tensions increased in Haiti, Guinea-Bissau and Moldova, where protests over endemic corruption and a lack of confidence in the government could escalate. In Africa, Boko Haram’s deadly attacks increased in northern Cameroon, and Burkina Faso was hit by an unprecedented terror attack. On the nuclear front, in East Asia, North Korea’s announcement that it had carried out a successful hydrogen bomb test was roundly condemned, while nuclear-related sanctions on Iran were rolled back in accordance with the July 2015 deal.
</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/150.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 20:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/150.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°149 | Tracking Conflict Worldwide</title>
      <description>The month saw an intensification of deadly violence in Burundi’s capital, Bujumbura, with over 80 people killed following clashes with security forces. The African Union Peace and Security Council (AU PSC) made a welcome statement of intent to deploy forces to halt the slide toward civil war and mass atrocities. In Afghanistan, fighting raged between government and Taliban forces, particularly in Helmand province, while in Djibouti, Ethiopia and Niger, political tensions heightened. In a positive step forward, a peace deal was signed in Libya but uncertainties remain over the viability of the agreement. As stressed by Jean-Marie Guéhenno, President and CEO of the International Crisis Group, in today’s Ten Conflicts to Watch in 2016, it “should be seen as a beginning, not an end, to the peace process”.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/149.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2016/149.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°148 | Tracking Conflict Worldwide</title>
      <description>November saw further military escalation and setbacks in Syria, particularly after Turkey shot down a Russian warplane it claimed had violated its airspace. Meanwhile, several countries faced extremist attacks claimed by the Islamic State (IS), including in Lebanon, France and Bangladesh. Violence also rose in Turkey between the state and Kurdish insurgents. In Venezuela, political tensions and violence increased ahead of parliamentary elections scheduled for 6 December and could worsen, while both Nepal and Kosovo faced deepening political crises. In a positive step forward, Burkina Faso and Myanmar experienced peaceful and openly-contested elections last month.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/148.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 14:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/148.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°147 | Tracking Conflict Worldwide</title>
      <description>As armed conflicts in Afghanistan, Iraq, Nigeria, South Sudan, Syria, Yemen, and elsewhere continued to inflict much suffering and instability around the world, the heads of the UN and International Committee of the Red Cross issued an unprecedented joint warning about the impact of today’s conflicts on civilians and called on states to redouble their efforts to find sustainable solutions to conflicts. Welcoming the call to action, Jean-Marie Guéhenno, President &amp; CEO of the International Crisis Group, said: “It is imperative that the world do much more to respond to early warning signs and prevent wars breaking out in the first place”. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/147.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 18:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/147.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°146</title>
      <description>In September, sectarian violence flared up again in the Central African Republic, while Burundi’s political deadlock increasingly turned into a deadly conflict. Yemen’s and Syria’s conflicts further intensified, with a significant toll on civilians, and Afghanistan’s and Somalia’s long-running insurgencies made substantial gains. Meanwhile, Burkina Faso and Tajikistan saw political crises bringing the prospect of renewed instability, and rising violence threatened peace efforts in Turkey and Mozambique. In contrast, Colombia’s peace process received a major boost with a breakthrough agreement on transitional justice, and Guatemala took a step to overcome a legacy of impunity. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/146.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/146.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°145</title>
      <description>Political crises and violent protests rocked a number of countries in August, including Guatemala, Nepal, Lebanon and Iraq, where popular unrest threatens to topple the government and overturn the post-2003 political order. Deadly conflict worsened in Yemen, Afghanistan and Kashmir, while violence increased in Burundi following President Nkurunziza’s successful run for a third term, and instability remained the norm in the Central African Republic where UN peacekeeping efforts faced a series of setbacks. A border crisis also prompted a dangerous spike in tensions between Colombia and Venezuela. On a positive note, August saw a peace agreement in South Sudan, strengthened prospects for political and constitutional reform in Sri Lanka, and an important political agreement ahead of October elections in Guinea. 
</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/145.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/145.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°144</title>
      <description>July saw a worsening of the situation in Yemen, where nearly 2,000 civilians have been killed since the war started in March, while in Turkey a dramatic escalation in violence led to the collapse of the state’s two-year-old ceasefire with Kurdish insurgents, and the launch of attacks on Islamic State (IS, formerly ISIL) positions in Syria. Meanwhile, a surge in clashes in Kashmir aggravated tensions between India and Pakistan, attacks by IS-linked militants escalated in Egypt, and Cameroon and Chad were both targeted by deadly and potentially destabilising Boko Haram raids and bombings. In contrast, the Colombian government and FARC rebels took steps to bring the peace process back on course after a series of setbacks, and South Sudan is faced with a unique chance to negotiate an end to its devastating conflict. Lastly, the nuclear agreement reached between the P5+1/EU3+3 and Iran in mid-July, provided it is approved by lawmakers on all sides, could mark a historic victory for diplomatic efforts in the face of entrenched global security challenges.
</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/144.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/144.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°143</title>
      <description>Extremist violence again dominated the month, with deadly attacks hitting Tunisia, Kuwait and Chad, while in Afghanistan the Taliban made further territorial gains and launched an unprecedented number of attacks. Burundi’s political crisis deepened as its ruling party held parliamentary elections despite widespread domestic and international objections. A rejection of Myanmar’s Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement (NCA) text by armed group leaders threatened to halt progress on the country’s peace process for the coming year. Nepal, meanwhile, made a significant step forward in its long-delayed constitution drafting process, a major part of its 2006 peace deal. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/143.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/143.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°142</title>
      <description>Burundi’s violent pre-election crisis prompted increasing alarm over the potential for open conflict. Meanwhile, fighting escalated dramatically in Afghanistan, South Sudan and Yemen in May, and Colombia’s peace agreement looked further imperilled as FARC suspended their ceasefire. A high-level defection to Islamic State from Tajikistan and a horrific attack on minorities in Pakistan were a stark reminder of ongoing destabilising extremist threats in these countries. May also saw a marked rise in geopolitical tensions in the South China Sea, developments in North Korea’s nuclear weapons systems, and a worsening of Macedonia’s political crisis. In contrast, both the Philippines and Cyprus made progress to resolve decades-old conflicts.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/142.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 16:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/142.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°141</title>
      <description>An agreement on the framework for a Joint Plan of Action on Iran’s nuclear enrichment program in early April marked a major step forward. However, mid-month, Colombia’s peace process suffered a serious blow when Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) fighters killed government soldiers in an ambush; and fighting resumed in Ukraine between the military and separatist forces. The announced end of Saudi Arabia’s five-week airstrike campaign in Yemen on 21 April brought few tangible results: missile strikes continued as the humanitarian situation became increasingly dire. Violent protests erupted in Burundi late month ahead of crucial presidential elections in June, and in Chad where popular discontent spilled over into violence. South Sudan and Kashmir saw their worst violence in months, while an earthquake in Nepal on 25 April killed thousands, amid the country’s ongoing political impasse. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/141.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/141.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°140</title>
      <description>March saw significant improvements in resolving longstanding conflicts, particularly in Myanmar and Colombia. However, Yemen’s political crisis tipped into all out-war, and fighting increased again in South Sudan following suspension of the peace talks. In Africa, election-related tensions worsened ahead of Burundi’s June presidential elections, while renewed international support to Guinea-Bissau gave a lift to political stability and reform. In a significant development for West Africa and beyond, Nigeria witnessed, for the first time in its history, the ousting of a ruling party through national elections, with Muhammadu Buhari’s victory in the 28 March presidential elections. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/140.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/140.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°139</title>
      <description>In February, the political crisis worsened in Yemen, whose territorial disintegration is in danger of accelerating, while in Bangladesh political violence threatens to further destabilise the country; Venezuela’s downward spiral also continued amid deep political polarisation. Deadly violence rose in Libya, where the prospects of a diplomatic solution to the internal conflict receded further; in Syria, where the regime and its allies initiated a major campaign against rebels in the south; and in areas affected by the Boko Haram insurgency in Nigeria and Niger. Serious fighting in Myanmar’s Kokang region undermined the ongoing peace talks, while a new peace deal for Ukraine was followed by major military defeat for the government in the east.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/139.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 13:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/139.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°138</title>
      <description>The year opened with a worsening of the ongoing conflicts in Yemen, Nigeria and Ukraine, each with potentially major regional implications. Violence escalated in Sudan, as well as in Lebanon's Tripoli and along its southern border with Israel, and a deadly clash between police and militants in the southern Philippines threatened to derail the peace process there. In South Asia, both Bangladesh and Nepal saw political tensions intensify. On a positive note, the Sri Lanka elections resulted in a peaceful transition of power from long-time President Mahinda Rajapaksa to Maithripala Sirisena, despite initial fears of election-related violence. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/138.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 08:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/138.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°137</title>
      <description>December saw a significant deterioration of the security situation – compared to the previous month – in nine countries or conflict situations in the world, including in South Asia (Pakistan and India), and East Africa (South Sudan and Kenya). There is a risk of increased violence in the coming month in Sudan, where major offensives are anticipated on the heels of a failure in the peace talks; in Sri Lanka, in the context of the 8 January elections; and in Haiti, where the current president could rule by decree unless parliament's mandate, due to expire on 12 January, is extended. On a positive note, the Colombia peace talks emerged strengthened in December, and relations between Cuba and the U.S. dramatically improved.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/137.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2015/137.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°136</title>
      <description>In Kenya an Al-Shabaab attack on a Nairobi-bound bus from Mandera on 22 November left 28 of the 60 passengers dead. The attackers deliberately targeted those passengers who were not Muslim or Somali. The government swiftly retaliated, with the Kenyan Defence Forces launching airstrikes on Al-Shabaab bases in Somalia and reportedly killing over 100 militants including, according to the government, the planners of the attack. Violence in Kenya’s coastal region left six youths dead after around twenty attacked Nyali military barracks in Mombasa and an administration police post in Malindi on 3 November. Religious tensions mounted as throughout November police raided and closed four Mombasa mosques with alleged links to Al-Shabaab. Hundreds of youths were arrested during the raids. Three of the mosques have now reopened but tensions remain high.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-136.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 16:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-136.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°135</title>
      <description>After a rainy season lull, South Sudan’s warring parties are preparing for major offensives with the Sudan People’s Liberation Army-In Opposition (SPLA-IO) this week launching attacks on Bentiu, capital of oil-producing Unity state (see our recent Conflict Alert). Hardliners in the government and the SPLA-IO appear determined to settle the conflict through war. Despite some signs of progress, nine months of peace talks have seen few results; instead, militias and self-defence forces are proliferating as their interests splinter, with many not effectively under the command and control of either main faction. Renewed conflict risks exacerbating widespread displacement and famine, as well as precipitating more atrocity crimes. </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-135.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 13:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-135.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°134</title>
      <description>The U.S. expanded its aerial campaign against Islamic State (IS) militants in late September with strikes in Syria’s north and east. The operation, which targets both IS and fighters linked to al-Qaeda’s central leadership and the affiliated group Jabhat al-Nusra, risks alienating other rebel groups in Syria and strengthening support for IS. The mainstream armed opposition faced another serious blow when most of the senior leadership of the influential group Ahrar as-Sham was killed in an unexplained bomb blast in early September. Meanwhile, IS continued its advance on the ground, including around the predominantly Kurdish city Kobani near the Turkish border causing some 160,000 Kurds to flee. (See our recent report and commentary on the possible fall of greater Aleppo and the impact this could have on the wider Syrian rebellion). </description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-134.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 09:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-134.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrisisWatch N°133</title>
      <description>The fight for control of Libya between the Misrata-led Islamist-leaning coalition and the Zintan-led forces is escalating by the day. Hundreds have been killed and thousands displaced in over six weeks of clashes and heavy artillery fire. The Misrata side emerged victorious in the battle over Tripoli’s international airport, taking control of the capital, and made advances around Benghazi, but the larger political divide remains unresolved. A newly formed parliament convened in Tobruk and has the backing of the Zintan-led anti-Islamists and the international community; but the previous legislature in Tripoli challenges its authority. Without a minimum of consensus, Libya is likely to have two ineffectual governments with militias exerting real control on the ground.</description>
      <link>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-133.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.crisisgroup.org/en/publication-type/crisiswatch/2014/crisiswatch-133.aspx</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
